Russell Chapman

429 Navajo Ave, Simla CO chpmnrssll@gmail.com (719) 541 5607

I've been programming for more than 20 years and have studied a wide variety of languages and computer science topics. Real-time graphics, web application development, and open source often grab my attention. At one time, I was a certified diesel mechanic; but due to back problems and spinal fusion surgery, I've decided to further pursue my career as a developer instead. More info about me can be found on my portfolio site at https://chpmnrssll.github.io/

Skills

- Content management systems (WordPress, custom)
- Static site generators (Jekyll, Hugo, Nuxt.is, VuePress)
- Responsive design (HTML5, CSS3, BEM, Sass, Stylus)
- · JavaScript, Node.js, Google Apps Script, PHP
- Backbone, jQuery, Vue.js, Express
- · Bower, Gulp, Grunt, NPM, Webpack
- OOP, MVC, REST, API, SPA, PWA
- 2D/3D Graphics, SVG, Canvas, WebGL
- SQL, NoSQL, MongoDB, JSON, CSV, XML
- DevOps, CI/CD, Docker, Linux, Bash, SSH, Git

Experience

upWork/oDesk - Full Stack Developer

2013 ~ present

Worked with various clients (worldwide) as a contractor/freelance developer. Detailed work history and feedback is available on my upWork profile page: https://www.upwork.com/fl/russellchapman

Like Minds Design - PHP Developer

03.2013 - 07.2013

Developed custom WordPress plugin and integrated into Mississippi Court Reporters Associations' new membership site: http://mscra.com/. More information about this project is available at: https://chpmnrssll.github.io/posts/about/MCRA

Freelance - Web Developer

1999 ~ 2013

Developed several websites ranging from static HTML to custom content management systems in PHP. More information available here: https://chpmnrssll.github.io/aluminium-spider/pages/portfolio/

Other

2005 ~ 2010

Worked as a parts counter, service writer, and ASE certified diesel mechanic at Travel Centers of America in Limon, CO. Also contracted as on-call/emergency roadside service provider in the Colorado Springs area.

Projects

Multithreaded Downloader for Backblaze B2

05.2018 - 07.2018

A browser-based multi-threaded downloader implemented in vanilla JavaScript.

More info: https://chpmnrssll.github.io/aluminium-spider/pages/multithread/

Portfolio Site

08.2017 - Current

Progressive Web App built with Jekyll static site generator.

- Handwritten modern JavaScript
- Offline service worker caching (Workbox.js)
- · Routing and animated page transitions
- App-shell model (PRPL pattern)

Live: https://chpmnrssll.github.io/

Source: https://github.com/chpmnrssll/chpmnrssll.github.io

VuePress (beta version): https://chpmnrssll.github.io/aluminium-spider/

Education

edX/BerkeleyX - Computer Science 2012

- CS169.1x: Software as a Service SaaS, Ruby on Rails https://verify.edx.org/cert/5e306e9de87e4b699e30024caa925ff7
- CS188.1x: Artificial Intelligence Machine Learning, Python https://verify.edx.org/cert/3e462d2a82e94c4da653c63924dbc56a

Pikes Peak Community College - Computer Science

1997 ~ 2011

- DRT 283 Advanced Animation
- DRT 201 Intro to Computer Animation
- CSC 161 Computer Science II, C++
- CSC 160 Computer Science I, C++
- AST 102 Astronomy II *
- AST 101 Astronomy I *
- SPS 101 Spaceflight *
- MAT 075 Pre-Algebra

^{*} NASA Scholorship program